Noah Arcand Da Silva

IT AND NETWORK TECHNICIAN · SELF-EMPLOYER

Ottawa, Ontario, Canada

【 (+1) 613-883-5593 | 🗷 noah@noahdasilva.com | 🧥 www.noahdasilva.com | 🖸 n0ahdasilva | 🛅 n0ahdasilva

"Own the day!"

Summary.

Current Site Reliability Engineer at start-up company Kasa. 7+ years experience specializing in the backend development, infrastructure automation, and computer hacking/security. Super nerd who loves Vim, Linux and OS X and enjoys to customize all of the development environment. Interested in devising a better problem-solving method for challenging tasks, and learning new technologies and tools if the need arises.

Education

Carleton University (School of Information Technology)

BACHELOR OF INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY, MAJOR IN NETWORK TECHNOLOGY

• Entrance Scholarship given to students entering Carleton University with excellent academic standing.

Algonquin College (School of Advanced Technology)

ADVANCED TECHNOLOGY DIPLOMA

• Entrance Scholarship given to students entering Carleton University with excellent academic standing.

Ottawa, Canado

Sep. 2019 - Apr. 2023

Ottawa. Canado

Sep. 2019 - Apr. 2023

Skills_

DevOps Virtual Machines, Linux/Unix, Windows Server, Docker, Kubernetes

Back-endDjango, PHP, REST APIFront-endHTML, CSS, Javascript, ReactProgrammingPython, Java, CPP, LaTeX

Languages French, English

Experience

Peano Ottawa & Montreal, Canada

IT - Network & Hardware Technologies

• Design, deploy, and maintain websites for our businesses.

- Respond to user requests for service, troubleshoot problems and help develop solutions.
- · Support PC hardware components, desktop operating system software, and application software.
- Perform minor repairs to equipment and arrange for other servicing needs.
- Identify and report system issues to vendors. Monitor and test resolution of those issues sent to vendors.
- Monitor antivirus software and updates, and repair computers infected with spyware, adware and/or viruses. Monitor backup systems and procedures to ensure data security.
- Record activities, solutions, and other responses to request for service.
- Contribute to technical documentation and participate in policy, procedure, and standards development. Assist in maintaining inventory records and documentation for equipment.
- Consult with vendors, perform research, and evaluate products to assist in the selection and purchase of equipment and installation or upgrade of systems
- Develop and provide user training for basic hardware and software use.
- Provide backup technical support for network including router, firewall, and wireless access point.
- · Perform other duties/projects as assigned.

Self-employment Ottawa, Canada

Web Design & Computer/Network Technician

- Design, deploy, and maintain websites for small businesses and individuals.
- · Optimize and expand home networks.
- · Build computers according to the clients' needs and budget.
- Conduct hardware and software troubleshooting to repair and maximize the performance of computers.
- Write articles on technology topics of interest (security, decentralization, innovation, ...)

May 2018 - Present

May 2021 - Present

Farm Boy

IT TECHNICIAN | HIGH SCHOOL CO-OP

- Mar. 2018 May 2018 • Repair and upgrade computers, Macs, phones, and laptops.
- Set up phones, laptops, and workstations for staff.
- · Ensure that inventory is properly maintained.
- · Learn about scripting and networking.

Extracurricular Activity

PoApper (Developers' Network of POSTECH)

CORE MEMBER & PRESIDENT AT 2013

Jun. 2010 - Jun. 2017

- Reformed the society focusing on software engineering and building network on and off campus.
- Proposed various marketing and network activities to raise awareness.

PLUS (Laboratory for UNIX Security in POSTECH)

MEMBER

Sep. 2010 - Oct. 2011

- · Gained expertise in hacking & security areas, especially about internal of operating system based on UNIX and several exploit techniques.
- Participated on several hacking competition and won a good award.
- Conducted periodic security checks on overall IT system as a member of POSTECH CERT.
- Conducted penetration testing commissioned by national agency and corporation.

Honors & Awards

DOMESTIC

2019 **FOCUS Recognition Award**, High School — Outstanding performance & dedication to the FOCUS program